Guide to the Time Inc. Records Overview 1853-2015 MS 3009
New-York Historical Society
- RG 31. Time Inc. Annual Reports (1922-2016)
  Annual Reports includes annual reports for Time Inc. and later Time Warner Inc. after the merger in 1989. America Online, Inc. (AOL) includes reports sent to the library for use as reference at the time of that merger. Annual reports may include accompanying financial reports, fact books, or Year in Review.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Annual Reports.
- RG 32. Time Inc. Time Covers (1923-2015)
  Time Covers contains a collection of covers removed from the rest of the magazine dating from 1923 through July 2015. Later dates sometimes include the entire magazine. This is a collection created by the Time Inc. Library and Archives.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Time Covers.
- RG 33. Time Inc. Oral History Project Records (1984-1994)
  The Oral History Project Records include background preparation research, transcripts, and audiovisual material from interviews of Time Inc. staff conducted by the Time Inc. Archives between 1984 and 1994.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Oral History Project Records.
- RG 34. Time Inc. Sports Illustrated Editorial Records (1969-1988)
  Sports Illustrated launched on August 16, 1954 as a weekly magazine with managing editor Sidney James and publisher Harry Phillips. The Editorial Records are primarily correspondence from senior editorial staff to place articles or excerpts from outside writers. There is a small amount of administrative records.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Sports Illustrated Editorial Records.
- RG 35. Time Inc. Sports Illustrated Publishing and Business Records (1950s-1993)
  Sports Illustrated launched on August 16, 1954 as a weekly magazine with managing editor Sidney James and publisher Harry Phillips. The Sports Illustrated (SI) Publishing and Business Records contain files from the deparments in charge of permissions, advertising sales, advertising promotion, merchandising, and market research.
  This record group contains extensive records on the early years of SI including early memoranda from managing editor James in the merchandising files. It also contains extensive records documenting the promotion of SI, particularly to potential advertisers, through awards ceremonies, collaborative events with communities, and scripted presentations to a variety of advertisers during SI's first year of publication. The advertising promotion files also include hundreds of taped interviews with sports figures which SI sent out as part of a tape service to radio and television stations.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Sports Illustrated Publishing and Business Records.
- RG 36. Time Inc. Production Department Records (1947-1969)
  The Production Department was responsible for overseeing the production of Time Inc. magazines. One aspect of this was overseeing the supply of paper products from the East Texas Pulp and Paper Company (Eastex).
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Production Department Records.
- RG 37. Time Inc. Comptroller Records (1957-1982)
  A collection of material produced during the comptroller's duties of supervising accounting and financial reporting. Includes material on accounting procedures and codes, accounts payable and receivable, balance sheets, lease agreements, and other financial information.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Comptroller Records.
- RG 38. Time Inc. Time Annotated Bound Issues (1933-2002)
  Time Annotated Bound Issues consists of 249 volumes of bound issues of Time magazine (1933-1934, 1940-2002) and one volume of Letters magazine (1934-1937). The issues of Time are noted as "marked" copies because they include annotations on various articles, primarily the initials of the writer, editor and researcher of the piece. The annotations also include brief observations on various matters of style, word choice, and the like, and paper inserts with count lists of international editions and other information.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Time Annotated Bound Issues.
- RG 39. Time Inc. Annex Files (1854, 1909, 1923-2014)
  The Time Inc. Annex Files is an assembled collection created by the Time Inc. archives of materials considered too bulky or infrequently requested to be housed in the main archives. Records in the Annex Files seem to be an extension of the of the materials in the Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1) and document the history of Time Inc. as an organization with information on each publication and many departments at Time Inc. The collection is largely made up of records pertaining to the development of magazines, The March of Time, Home Box Office (HBO), Time-Life Books, and information on public affairs programs and events, international business, and advertising studies and surveys.
  Additional records on the divisions, departments and offices at Time Inc. are also in the Time Inc. Reference Files (MS 3009-RG 3).
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Annex Files.
- RG 40. Time Inc. Magazine Development Group Records (1967-1987, 2003)
  The Magazine Development Group (MDG) Records contains records from two versions of this group documenting the processes for and progress on development of new magazines at Time Inc. between 1973 and 1987. The first MDG developed and launched People and Life Special Reports. The second MDG worked extensively on Picture Week.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Magazine Development Group Records.
- RG 41. Time Inc. Video Group Records (1934-1989)
  The Time Inc. Video Group Records contain materials documenting Time Inc.'s work in the cable, film, and television industries. The Video Group oversaw the departments and subsidiaries that worked directly in these industries. Included in this record group are materials created by the staff of Time-Life Films, Time-Life Video, Time-Life Broadcast/Time-Life Broadcast Inc., Time-Life Cable, Home Box Office (HBO), and Manhattan Cable Television (MCTV).
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Video Group Records.
- RG 42. Time Inc. Harry Harding Files on Corporate Identity (1967-1971)
  Corporate executive Harry Harding's files document his work on Time Inc.'s corporate identity, specifically attempting to create a new corporate logo or trademark for use throughout the company.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Harry Harding Files on Corporate Identity.
- RG 43. Time Inc. Discover Publishing and Business Records (1980-1987)
  The Discover Publishing and Business Records contain files from publisher Bruce Barnet documenting the final review of feasibility of Discover and its sale.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Discover Publishing and Business Records.
- RG 44. Time Inc. Time Canada Ltd. Records (1954-1975, 1995-1999)
  The Time Canada Ltd. Records contain the records from the business side of the subsidiary of Time Inc. that published the Canadian edition of Time. Records are primarily from President Don Brown, and Managing Directors Lawrence Laybourne, Steve LaRue, and Bradley Gundy. There are a few folders of operating statements and from the Promotion Department.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Time Canada Ltd. Records.
- RG 45. Time Inc. New Media Records: Editor Daniel Okrent Files (1989-2001)
  The Time Inc. New Media Records contain Daniel Okrent's files created while he was Editor of New Media and document this department's management of Time Inc.'s internet projects including websites for each magazine.
  Click here to link to the Time Inc. New Media Records: Editor Daniel Okrent Files.
- RG 46. Time Inc. Publicity Files (1923-1984)
  The Time Inc. Publicity Files are a collection of press clippings documenting outside perception of Time Inc. regarding the company's publications, activities, and personnel.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Publicity Files.
- RG 47. Time Inc. Editorial Services Records (1966-1977, 1991-2003)
  The Time Inc. Editorial Services Records documents the activities of various departments and offices within this division that supported all editorial and publishing divisions at Time Inc. The majority of records are from several photograph syndication services at Time Inc. Also included are office files from the Editorial Production/Copy Processing department and photographs of staff events.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Editorial Services Records.
- RG 48. Time Inc. Realia Collection (1937-2015)
  The collection is composed of a wide variety of objects collected by the Time Inc. Archives. The most common type of objects are those given to advertisers as a promotional gimmick to encourage advertisment in Time Inc. magazines, awards given to Time Inc., its magazines, or staff, and items branded with the logos of Time Inc. magazines given to Time Inc. employees as gifts or to subscribers as promotions.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Realia Collection.
- RG 49. Time Inc. TV-Cable Week Publishing and Business Records (1981-1983, 1990)
  This collection contains records from publisher Christopher Meigher regarding TV-Cable Week, a short-lived Time Inc. cable television listings magazine.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the TV-Cable Week Publishing and Business Records.
- RG 50. Time Inc. Corporate Circulation Records (1940-1987)
  Corporate Circulation was a department of Time Inc. that supervised marketing of subscriptions for all of the company's magazines which included in-house creation of promotions as well as dealing with outside advertising agencies. The records consist of information on promotion efforts for specific magazines, information on magazine subscribers, and correspondence and agreements with foreign distributors.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Circulation Records.
- RG 51. Time Inc. Atlantic Recording Company and Elektra Entertainment Records (1964-1993)
  Atlantic Recording Corporation and Elektra Entertainment are music record labels owned by Warner Communications at the time of its merger with Time Inc. The labels were then managed under the Time Warner Entertainment division. The collection contains print-outs of sales data for artists signed with both labels.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Atlantic Recording Company and Elektra Entertainment Records.
- RG 52. Time Inc. Travel Services Records (1989-1995)
  Time Inc. Travel Services arranged business travel for Time Inc. employees. The collection comes from the files of Tom McDermott, Travel Services Director in 1995.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Travel Services Records.
- RG 53. Time Inc. Company Services Records (1969-1983)
  Time Inc. Company Services was founded in the late 1940s to carry out functions not directly related to the production of Time Inc. magazines or other products. The collection consists of flight logs of an aircraft owned by Time Inc. and invoices for purchase of various items of office furniture and equipment.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Company Services Records.
- RG 54. Time Inc. Selling Areas-Marketing, Inc. (SAMI) Records (1985)
  Selling Areas-Marketing, Inc. (SAMI) was a company owned by Time Inc. that produced reports on the sale of consumer goods and offered them for sale by subscription. The collection consists of examples of these reports and correspondence.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Selling Areas-Marketing, Inc. (SAMI) Records.
- RG 55. Time Inc. Sports Illustrated for Kids Records (1987-1996)
  Sports Illustrated for Kids (SIFK) was developed by Sports Illustrated staff starting around 1987 and launched in January 1989. Records primarily document the development of SIFK and include prospectuses, circulation plans, marketing plans, advertising plans, story list ideas, kids survey results, and a copy of the first issue.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Sports Illustrated for Kids Records.
- RG 56. Time Inc. International Records (1957-1974, 1984-1997)
  Time Inc. International marketed and published Time Inc. magazines outside the United States. It set up offices in various cities around the world to work on regional version of magazines, made deals to license the names of Time Inc. magazines to foreign publishers, and occasionally published original magazines in foreign territories. The collection consists of correspondence, reports, data on sales and expenses, projections and propositions for the future, and printed presentations. This record group includes files from earlier divisions that provided the same function such as Time Life International (TLI) and Corporate International.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. International Records.
- RG 57. Time Inc. Postal Rates Records (1949-1978)
  When postal rates or other aspects of law governing postal delivery were changed, or may be changed, in ways Time Inc. found unfavorable, it advocated for its position with Congress and the public. This collection contains information used in those activities such as bills put before Congress on the topic of postal rates and law, correspondence between people within Time Inc. and with members of Congress, proceedings of the Postal Commission including witness testimony, reports on the costs of postal delivery, and examples of Time Inc.'s direct mail marketing.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Postal Rates Records.
- RG 58. Time Inc. Consumer Marketing Records (2000)
  Consumer Marketing was a division within Time Inc. which had charge of all activities in support of direct marketing for Time Inc. magazines. The collections consists of a binder of statistics on the sales, circulation, and net profit or loss of various Time Inc. magazines.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Consumer Marketing Records.
- RG 60. Evening Star Newspaper Co. Records (1911-1972)
  The Evening Star Newspaper Co. was the publisher of the Washington, D.C. daily newspaper The Evening Star. Founded in 1852, the newspaper held several names during its existence. Time Inc. purchased the newspaper in 1978 when it was known as The Washington Star. This collection contains company records from prior to Time Inc.'s acquisition including staff newsletters, a handwritten record of births of children to employees, and accounting books.
  Records on The Washington Star finances after Time Inc.'s acquisition are in the Time Inc. Time-Life News Service Records (MS 3009-RG 14).
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Evening Star Newspaper Co. Records.
- RG 61. Time Inc. Information Systems Records (1980-1986)
  The Information Systems Group was created by Time Inc. to plan and oversee use of computer and data processing resources by employees of the company. The collection consists of studies on the creation of a corporate data center and personnel/payroll computer systems, history of the data center, and manuals for the use of computer services offered by the Group.
  Click here to link to the Guide to the Time Inc. Information Systems Records